export const quizEntries = [{
    title: "What Does Reading Intervention Look & Sound Like?",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 0,
    Question: "When you're leading reading interventions, should you: ",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Teach a comprehensive approach",
    option2: "Teach to the students' assessed weaknesses",
    option3: "",
    option4: "",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 2,
    explanation: "A 2018 meta-analysis by Mathew Hall and Mathew Burns, of 26 experimental or quasi-experimental studies on reading interventions found: 'Interventions were more effective if they were targeted to a specific skill (g = 0.65), then as part of a comprehensive intervention program that addressed multiple skills (g = 0.35).'",
    explanation2: "Interventions that targeted student deficits were twice as effective!",
    cautionLevel: "",
    caution: "[Citations needed]",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "'Advanced Phonemic Awareness' 1",
    subtitle: "When Should T's Use this Practice?",
    id: 1,
    nestlevel: "0",
    has_subitems: false,
    subitems: [],
    has_XPs: false,
    XPs: [],
    Question: "Teaching 'Advanced Phonemic Awareness' involves:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Rhyming",
    option2: "Blending and segmenting onset-rimes",
    option3: "Phoneme addition and deletion",
    option4: "Phoneme Manipulation",
    correctAnswer: 3,
    explanation: "This video illustrates: Phoneme Addition",
    caution: "The practice has not yet been studied.",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "'Advanced Phonemic Awareness' 2",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 2,
    Question: "The practice of teaching 'Advanced Phonemic Awareness' was first suggested by:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Marie Clay",
    option2: "David Kilpatrick",
    option3: "Heggerty",
    option4: "Fontas & Pinnell",
    correctAnswer: 2,
    explanation: "Kilpatrick discovered a pattern of how some struggling children were succeeding, and hypothesized that this additional skill-building practice might help others.",
    caution: "The practice has not yet been studied, and Kilpatrick regrets the choice of name.",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "MTSS and Universal screeners",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 3,
    Question: "Typically, an SOR-based school will use a universal screener to assign students to:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Tier One",
    option2: "Tier Two",
    option3: "Tier Three",
    option4: "Tiers two and three",
    option5: "None of the Above",
    correctAnswer: 5,
    explanation: "In an MTSS school, Tiers are not a class of student. Tiers represent a system for giving each student exactly the instruction and practice they need.",
    explanation2: "In fact, the most common use of a universal screener may be to change what's taught in Tier one.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Developmental Language Disorder",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 4,
    Question: "Developmental Language Disorder is best described by:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "a brain-based developmental disorder that is a subset (type of) dyslexia",
    option2: "a brain-based developmental disorder that contributes to reading difficulties, but occurs in children who do not have dyslexia ",
    option3: "a brain-based developmental disorder that includes dyslexia as one of its instances",
    option4: "a brain-based developmental disorder that contributes to reading difficulties, and may be accompanied by dyslexia in some children.",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 4,
    explanation: "Children with DLD have issues with languge comprehension--not word recognition, but with understanding language.",
    explanation2: "DLD is more common than dyslexia (1 in 14 kids). A child may have DLD, Dyslexia, or both.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Structured Linguistic Literacy",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 5,
    Question: "Structured Linguistic Literacy is:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "an alternative approach to more traditional phonics instruction that initially emphasizes activities like: segment sounds first, write sounds next, and blend sounds back into a word",
    option2: "an approach to teaching language development (word meaning, phrases, sentence structure, etc.) at the k-5 level.",
    option3: "an innovative, but not-yet-significantly-used commercial program for developing word recognition in children.",
    option4: "a made-up term designed to poke fun at the many buzzwords which have come to surround the teaching of reading.",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 1,
    explanation: "Structured Linguistic Literacy is a new name for a speech-to-print approach to phonics.",
    explanation2: "",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Components of Instruction",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 6,
    Question: "According to the renowned literacy leader Timothy Shanahan, the general breakdown of an early literacy day is: ",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "~1/5 Phonemic Awareness, 1/5 Phonics, 1/5 Oral Fluency, 1/5 Vocabulary Development, and 1/5 Comprehension",
    option2: "~1/4 words, 1/4 text fluency, 1/4 comprehension, and 1/4 writing",
    option3: "~1/3 spelling & vocabulary, 1/3 sentence meaning, and 1/3 text comprehension",
    option4: "~1/3 reading fluency and 2/3 comprehension strategies and meaningful writing",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 2,
    explanation: "This is a rule of thumb, and all such rules are meant to be only rough approximations.",
    explanation2: "Yet the general idea is: begin the lesson by expanding either the decoding abilities of younger children, or the morphemic, vocabulary and spelling abilities of older children; then focus on a text each day, allowing students to analyse, discuss, and writie about it in various ways.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "While no exact research base can validate this as science, it reflects both the needs science has identified, and the practical realities of the classroom.",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Orthographic Mapping",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 7,
    Question: "Is there an age window for mastering orthographic mapping?",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Yes.",
    option2: "No.",
    option3: "",
    option4: "",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 1,
    explanation: "Much like speaking a foreign language without an accent, the window for effortless decoding begins to close around age 9.",
    explanation2: "While even adult dyslexics can benefit from learning basic phonics, many children who don't get this learning by ~age 9 will always suffer from that lack.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "[Citations needed]",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Progress Monitoring",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 8,
    Question: "Which of these is NOT a reason that the ORF (DIBELS/Acadience) has become the go-to progress monitoring tool for SOR professionals?",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "They are quick, and simple to administer and score, taking just a few minutes per student.",
    option2: "They show students' progress toward a rate of approximately 90-100 wcpm at the end of second grade, and 180 wcpm as adult readers.",
    option3: "They do not require a great deal of training to administer.",
    option4: "They measure students' oral language development.",
    option5: "They are a good measure of reading comprehension in lower grades.",
    correctAnswer: 4,
    explanation: "Oral language development should usually be more advanced than the skills being measured by ORF/DIBELS.",
    explanation2: "Children who are not advancing well in oral language development may need more Tier I, II, or III instruction.",
    cautionLevel: "",
    caution: "[Citations needed]",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Age of the Science of Reading",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 9,
    Question: "A convenient marker for dating the science of reading is:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "~The founding of the Harvard Reading Lab",
    option2: "Dehaene & others' use fMRI to demonstrate location of Visual Word Form Area",
    option3: "Seidenberg & McClelland's simulations supporting a model with phonological, orthographic, and semantic processors",
    option4: "Linnea Ehri coining the term 'Orthographic Mapping'",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 1,
    explanation: "Jeanne Chall founded the Harvard Reading Lab in 1966.",
    explanation2: "While much psychological research around reading proceeds this, and Chall's 1967 book, 'Learning to Read: The Great Debate' surveyed research from 1912 through 1965; the coordinated research from this point forward signals SOR as an integrated area of study.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "About Comprehension",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 10,
    Question: "Comprehension is best described as:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "A 'Pillar' of literacy",
    option2: "A skill, like decoding words",
    option3: "A condition created when the reader has sufficient word recognition skills, language comprehension knowledge, and background knowledge about the topic of the text",
    option4: "",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 3,
    explanation: "To comprehend text, the reader must have all three.",
    explanation2: "",
    cautionLevel: "",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Assessing Student Weaknesses",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 11,
    Question: "When we say 'assessed student weaknesses' with respect to reading skills, a Structured Literacy (SOR) approach often starts with a screener called Oral Reading Fluency. (Or DIBELS, or Acadience, or other brand name.)",
    questionP2: "What does ORF tell us that other assessments might not?",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "A student’s ability to read words in connected text",
    option2: "A student's speed and accuracy of reading, compared to peers.",
    option3: "It is an accurate indicator of reading comprehension.",
    option4: "a and b",
    option5: "a, b, and c",
    correctAnswer: 5,
    explanation: "For K-3, for most (9 of 10) students, ORF has been shown over the years to be a reliable predictor of student reading success, and an indicator of their ability to comprehend.",
    explanation2: "Dr. Stephanie Stollar's Reading Science Academy YouTube channel has an excellent explanation of this. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PgExOz1YMIw",
    cautionLevel: "",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Speech to Print",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 12,
    Question: "Speech to Print is:",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "an alternative approach to more traditional phonics instruction that initially emphasizes activities like: segment sounds first, write sounds next, and blend sounds back into a word",
    option2: "an approach to teaching language development (word meaning, phrases, sentence structure, etc.) at the k-5 level.",
    option3: "an innovative, but not-yet-significantly-used commercial program for developing word recognition in children.",
    option4: "",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 1,
    explanation: "Speech to Print can come in differnt forms, but is generally just a reordinging of the scope and sequence of the earliest phonics instruction.",
    explanation2: "It's also called 'Structured Linguistic Literacy'",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Orthographic Mapping",
    subtitle: "(Creating 'sight words')",
    id: 13,
    Question: "When children convert a word they see from an unknown word, to one they can decode, then to one they recognize instantly, we call this process 'orthographic mapping.",
    questionP2: "Is there an age window for mastering orthographic mapping?",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "Yes.",
    option2: "No.",
    option3: "",
    option4: "",
    option5: "",
    correctAnswer: 1,
    explanation: "Much like speaking a foreign language without an accent, the window for effortless decoding begins to close around age 9.",
    explanation2: "While even adult dyslexics can benefit from learning basic phonics, many children who don't get this learning by ~age 9 will always suffer from that lack.",
    cautionLevel: "a",
    caution: "[Citations needed]",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}, {
    title: "Age of the Science of Reading",
    subtitle: "",
    id: 14,
    Question: "The science of reading has essentially been around as a field for:",
    questionP2: "",
    answer_type: "mc",
    option1: "20 years",
    option2: "30 years",
    option3: "40 years",
    option4: "50 years",
    option5: "60 years",
    correctAnswer: 5,
    explanation: "While reading science has roots going back 100 years or more, a convenient marker for the birth of the field is the founding of the Harvard Reading lab in 1966.",
    explanation2: "The following year she published 'Learning to Read: the Great Debate', a compilation of research to date.",
    cautionLevel: "",
    caution: "[Citations needed]",
    closingText: "",
    closingText2: "",
    modal: ""
}]